Steve Holmes

East Morton, West Yorkshire; stevie.holmes@gmail.com

Business Intelligence Developer

I am highly numerate and technically skilled with a strong sense of integrity. I enjoy bringing a creative, analytical and logical approach to problem solving. Currently employed as Head of Technology at Pi Healthcare, I have over 19 years of experience developing data-driven analytical strategies that address business problems. I combine my management experience and technical understanding to bring value to businesses.

Skills

SQL Server; T-SQL; Excel; VBA; Office 365 suite; Power BI.

Microsoft Azure; SSIS; SSRS; SSAS; HES; SUS; SLAM; Various web design packages & processes. Agile development; Prince2 (practitioner - lapsed).

Information Governance; Stakeholder management; Problem solving; Data Analysis.

Experience

<u>Pi Healthcare</u> / Head of Technology August 2018 - present / Ilkley

Overall responsibility for all technology driven projects within the company, both client-focused and internal, including ongoing governance and maintenance.

Design & development of a bespoke online platform, including its underlying Azure SQL server relational database & integration and management of the various data sources.

Managing a team of five technical staff, providing mentoring, guidance and day-to-day support. Lead contact responsible for all technical stakeholder partnerships.

Appointed the Data Protection Officer responsible for ensuring the company is fully compliant with GDPR.

NHS Digital / Senior Business Intelligence Analyst (Contract) December 2017 - March 2018 / Leeds

Created a full life cycle of reporting suite, from requirement gathering, to data collating, Power BI report design and online publication.

Responsible for training and skills development to colleagues.

NHS Yorkshire & Humber CSU / Embed / Business Intelligence Developer (Contract) April 2013 - June 2017 / Bradford

Responsible for designing & generating multiple routine reports from various NHS datasets. Created bespoke tools to cater for various ad-hoc requests from internal & external customers. Designed a system to routinely collate irregular reports into a single database, to export into a suite of Service level agreement monitoring reports for distribution to customers.

<u>UKAR</u> / Management Information Analyst (Contract) July 2012 - March 2013 / Crossflatts

Produced ad-hoc analysis from confidential HR data.

Developed systems for fast and accurate production of HR focused MI reports.

<u>Self Employed</u> / Web design February 2011 - July 2012 / Home based

Started up and ran a web design company, gaining and improved knowledge of several software packages and languages as well as insights into all aspects of running a business.

Steve Holmes Curriculum Vitae: 20th Sep 2020 1/2

Aetna / Informatics Analyst

December 2008 - January 2011 / Home based

Analysed integrated healthcare data using descriptive and inferential statistics to create utilization, quality and cost containment summary information to assist in decision support. Defined, designed, developed and delivered care management nurse activity statistics after extensive liaison with senior nurses.

<u>Department of Health</u> / <u>GSS</u> / Statistician, Planning Manager and Analyst January 2003 - December 2008 / Leeds

Responsible for managing the process of collecting NHS plans from multiple (hundreds) of organisations.

Successfully collated NHS plans using new technology to an extremely tight deadline. Line management responsibility.

Responsible for collection, validation, maintenance and analysis of key NHS target data.

Providing ad-hoc analysis to senior management, commissioning the relevant source data.

Created a popular tool converting data held as old NHS organisations structure into a format in keeping with the latest configuration.

<u>Great Clothes</u> / Buying Analyst

September 2001 - January 2003 / Leeds

Allocated the annual purchasing budget of £8.5m and re-ordered stock worth £2.5m p.a. Automated many processes including an automated order sheet - produced through extensive liaison with internal stakeholders and the external I.T. systems provider.

Responsible for the complete reorganisation of the company's information structure, which improved efficiency in accessing data.

Various / Part time roles (temporary)

September 1995 - August 2001 / Leeds, Bradford, Manchester & Germany

Various part time roles for funding University & until gaining full time employment

Education

Manchester Metropolitan University / Part time

September 1995 - July 2000 / Manchester

B.Sc. (Hon's) Business Mathematics & Statistics, 2(ii)

South Craven School

September 1988 - July 1995 / North Yorkshire

3 A-Levels: Mathematics and Statistics, Economics, General Studies.

8 GCSE's: Grades A to C, including Mathematics & English

Interests

Sporting successes include completing the London marathon, a representative rugby league call up for Great Britain's Civil Service, and regular representation of football & rugby 7's for <u>HASSRA UK</u>. Other pastimes include motorcycling, computing, DIY, exercising and socialising.

References available upon request.